technospot.net 2019-12-02

# Privacy Policy

We use Ezoic to provide personalization and analytic services on this website, as such Ezoic's privacy policy is in effect and can be reviewed [here](https://g.ezoic.net/privacy/technospot.net).  

## Welcome to Technospot.Net Privacy Policy Page.

## Who we are

Our website address is https://www.technospot.net/blogs/

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms

We use the Jetpack Contact Form which sends email to the administrator of the website and also stores the data on the server. We occasionally delete those data.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

We use Google Analytics and WordPress Stats to track our website statistics.

## Who we share your data with

We do not share your data directly with anyone. However, Google AdSense, Google Analytics. Disqus Commenting, Gravatar.com, MAXCDN, may collect your data anonymously.

We also use Ezoic for managing advertisements. You can read their complete [Privacy Policy here.](https://g.ezoic.net/privacy/wpxbox.com)

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## Your contact information

While the best way to connect with us is using the [contact page](https://www.wpxbox.com/contact/), but if you have something very important here are the details.

 **Email Address:** [[email protected]](https://www.technospot.net/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

 **Our Location:** 23B N.S.Road 2nd Floor Room No 217 Kolkata 700001, India

 **Phone No:** 9674321169

## Additional information

### How we protect your data & What data breach procedures we have in place

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service. We use Disqus Commenting. We also have Akismet for spam detection.

We protect customer data by entirely using SSL/HTTPS throughout all our sites. This encrypts our user communications with the servers so personal identifiable information is never captured by third parties without authorization.

### What third parties we receive data from

We do not receive any specific data, but Google Analytics and Jetpack Stats give demographics data of our visitors. It helps us to understand if we are working correctly, and able to deliver the right content.

### What automated decision making and/or profiling we do with user data

We do not do any kind of profiling. However, if the user wants, his data related to comments can be exported and given to him.
